



## SOVANNMONYREAK HING

# PERSONAL PROFILE

Hello, world! When learning a programming language for the first time, programmers prefer to output. I am Sovannmonyreak Hing (nicknamed Rick), a 21-year-old Cambodian teenager who aspires to be a Googler because I believe in technology and its ability to enhance our daily lives. I am a Computer Science graduate student.

As an intern, I worked as a web developer and chatbot developer for Sousdey Cambodia (https://www.sousdeycambodia.co m/). In addition to my professional experience, I have been working since my sophomore year. However, my internship lasts around six months and allows me to work with well-known firms like Smart, Cellcard, and Chip Mong. Even so, that hasn't stopped me from pursuing additional real-world job experiences, so I've set myself up as a freelancer in web and chatbot programming. Aside from working and studying, I'm also developing a support system to assist the future generation of computer science students. These events include self-study assistance, coding, and a hackathon. Each of those exercises is code-related, but more importantly, it helps students learn the workflow of how to arrange their abilities with logic.

#### **GET IN CONTACT**

Mobile: +885 12 698206 rax@dvhub.space

Toul Sangke, Russey Keo, Phnom Penh, Cambodia

### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Hands-on SQL experience
- Javascript, Dart, PHP and Python experience
- Laravel MVC, Web API experience
- Working knowledge of C, C++, and C#

## **OTHER SKILLS**

- The ability to analyze complex technical information
- Can analyze, design and implement database structures
- Detail oriented
- Excellent problem solver

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[Unity-game-development] - [Smart Axiata Innovation Lab - Paragon University]	2017-2018
Unity 3D and 2D Game development self-taught	2017-2018
Zaman Youth Club - Paragon university (Somram Project)	2017-2018
Running a charity project at Chaba om pov (Public School)	2017-2019
Runner Up Paragon Hackathon	2020
You can code	2021
Paragon Hackathon Organizer	2021

#### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

Paragon University Computer Science (CS)	2017-Present
Zaman Internation School	2012-2017
Paññāsāstra International School (PSIS)	2011-2012
ChaktokMuk Primary School	2005-2011